你可没说戒备会这么森严
You didn't tell me there'd be such security.
他们把飞机起飞的时间提前了
They moved the flight forward.
我们还是得按照计划进行
We'll have to go ahead as planned anyway.
托罗，听起来像只公牛
Toro? Sounds like a load of bull.
詹姆斯
James.
千万要小心点
Please, be careful.
看呐，世界可真小，你也叫托罗
Well, it's a small world. You're a Toro, too.
我们迈阿密见
I'll see you in Miami.
（燃料不足）
请加满油
Fill her up, please.
东柏林
（英国大使官邸）
大使先生，您的客人都到了
Your guests have arrived, Ambassador.
亲爱的，我们该出去了
We should go, my dear.
好嘛
Well...
你变得越来越漂亮了
You become more beautiful every day.
- 我在这呢 - 当然了，我知道
- I'm over here. - Of course you are.
这位是我的新助理，佩内洛普·斯摩本小姐
And this is Miss Penelope Smallbone, my new assistant.
斯摩本小姐
Miss Smallbone.
钱班霓，我还能说什么呢？
What can I say, Moneypenny?
除了说她是这么的迷人，就像...
Except that she is as attractive and as charming...
- 就像我以前那样？ - 我没有这么说
- As I used to be? - I didn't say that.
詹姆斯，你可真会哄人
You're such a flatterer, James.
钱班霓，从来都没有，以后也不会有像你这么吸引我的人
Moneypenny, you know there never has been and never will be anybody but you.
你已经说过了
So you've told me.
- 欢迎来到环球出口公司 - 收下吧，亲爱的
- Welcome to Universal Exports. - Take it, dear.
这是你唯一能从他那得到的东西
That's all you'll ever get from him.
谢谢你，邦德中校
Thank you, Commander Bond.
你认识我吗？
Do you know me?
钱班霓小姐和我说过你
Miss Moneypenny described you.
你干的坏事她都知道
In nauseating detail.
真的吗？
Really?
我觉得你很适合在这里工作
I can see you're going to fit in here very nicely.
- 早上好，007 - 早上好，长官
- Good morning, 007. - Morning, sir.
- 部长 - 中校
- Minister. - Commander.
你应该认识吉姆·范宁，我们的艺术品专家
I think you know Jim Fanning, our art expert.
- 是的，你好，吉姆 - 詹姆斯
- Yes. Hello, Jim. - James.
你知道这是什么吗？
Do you know what this is?
长官，看起来像是法贝热彩蛋
It looks like a Faberge egg, sir.
这是卡尔·法贝热为俄罗斯王室制作的众多宝石彩蛋之一
One of the jewelled eggs by Carl Faberge as a gift for the Russian royal family.
价值连城，并且非常稀有
They're priceless and very rare.
这里面有一个雕刻的皇室马车的模型
This one contains a model of the imperial state coach.
- 007，你说的很好 - 谢谢你，长官
- Top marks, 007. - Thank you, sir.
只不过这是个赝品
Except it's a fake.
真的是这个，今天下午会在苏富比拍卖行拍卖
There's the real thing. It's being auctioned at Sotheby's this afternoon.
这个是今年第四个要拍卖的宝石彩蛋
This is the fourth egg to turn up at auction this year.
这次拍卖很不寻常 匿名的卖家，秘密的瑞士银行账户
It's from none of the usual sources. Anonymous seller, Swiss bank account.
我敢说卖家肯定是个俄国人
I'd say that the vendor was a Russian.
这个时候，它出现了
And now this turns up.
一个几乎可以乱真的赝品
A near-perfect forgery.
我觉得邦德中校应该和你一起去拍卖会
I think Commander Bond should accompany you to the sale.
这样就太好了，我正好需要一个助手
Splendid. I could use an extra pair of eyes.
我们可以去查一下卖家是谁
We could try and spot the seller.
他们通常都会表现的毫无兴趣或者趁机推高价格
They usually turn up out of interest or perhaps just to bump up the price.
谢谢你，范宁
Thank you, Fanning.
别客气
Not at all.
如果卖家是俄国人，这很可能是为海外情报活动
If it is the Russians, it may be an effort to raise currency
筹集资金，或者是为了偿还债务
for covert operations abroad or for payoffs.
无论如何，我们最好查出他们要干什么
Either way, we'd better find out what they're up to.
- 是，部长 - 007这是机密文件
- Yes, Minister. - Eyes only, 007.
“寻宝行动”
Operation Trove.
你会接替009的职务
You'll be replacing 009.
他在东德被杀，死的时候手里就拿着那枚彩蛋
He turned up dead in East Germany with that egg in his hand.
这就是全部线索了
There's not much to go on.
长官，我们还有一条线索
Well, we do have one lead, Minister.
“女士的藏品”
"Property of a Lady."
下一个议题是商讨与北约进行互相裁军的谈判条件
Next on the agenda is the continuing mutual disarmament talks with NATO.
我想你们应该都看过果戈理将军的报告了
I assume you've all read General Gogol's report.
里面写得非常详细
It seems very thorough.
谢谢你，主席同志
Thank you, Comrade Chairman.
我想我的观点已经表达的非常清楚了
I believe I express the opinion of everyone present
采用北约的方案并不会损害我们国家的国防体系
that adoption of NATO proposals does not compromise our defensive position.
- 主席同志 - 奥尔洛夫将军
- Comrade Chairman. - General Orlov.
果戈理将军真是太放肆了
General Gogol is presumptuous.
他的话只能代表他自己
He speaks for himself and others
还有那些无能之辈，这是不切实际的政策
who cling to timid, outdated and unrealistic policies.
我必须得提醒你们一下
Must I remind you, the committee,
在我们决定接受北约的裁军条件之前
of our overwhelming superiority over NATO forces
我们对他们有绝对优势
before we give it away?
我在东德可以直接调动的军队
In East Germany under my direct command,
一共有31个师，包括11个装甲师
I have 31 divisions, including 11 tank divisions
捷克斯洛伐克还有五个装甲师
and another five in Czechoslovakia.
作为支援，在俄罗斯西部边界还有60个师的兵力
In support, on the Russian western border are 60 divisions,
包括22个装甲师
including 22 tank divisions.
我们有十比一的优势
In all, a 10-1 advantage.
美国和西德军方最多只能动员十个装甲师的兵力
American and West German forces can field at most ten armoured divisions.
英国只是维持象征性的兵力
The British maintain only a token force.
我们已经用最新型的库图佐夫计算机进行了多次沙盘推演
We have played out a variety of attack strategies on the new Kutuzov computer
结论是从北方以十个师的兵力发起突然袭击
and find that a lightning thrust by ten armoured divisions from the north,
另外五个装甲师从捷克进攻，不管他们如何防御
and by five more through Czechoslovakia, lead to total victory in five days
五天之内我们就会取得全面胜利
against any possible defence scenario.
这简直是太疯狂了
This is absolute madness.
我们都知道这样做的后果
We know where it will end.
北约会使用核武器发起反击
NATO will counterattack with nuclear weapons.
绝对不会
Never.
西方世界腐败而又分裂
The West is decadent and divided.
他们不敢去承担受到我方核反击的风险
It has no stomach to risk our atomic reprisals.
在欧洲每天都有抗议者要求单方面放弃使用核武器
Throughout Europe, daily demonstrations demand unilateral nuclear disarmament.
我们没有必要去为了
I see no reason to risk war
你个人的狂热和好战而冒险去发动战争
to satisfy your personal paranoia and thirst for conquest.
我们必须得先处理国内的一系列紧急问题
We must turn our energies to pressing domestic problems.
- 果戈理将军，我提醒你一下... - 同志们，坐下
- General Gogol, let me remind you... - Comrades, sit down.
- 我告诉你... - 你们两个都是
- I wish to tell you... - Both of you.
全球社会主义要依靠和平手段来实现
World socialism will be achieved peaceably.
我们的军事力量是防卫性的
Our military role is strictly defensive.
奥尔洛夫将军，你明白吗
Is that understood, General Orlov?
果戈理将军，你可以继续了
General Gogol, would you continue?
谢谢你，主席同志，接下来我要说一下报告中的重点内容
Thank you, Comrade Chairman. I will now turn to the specifics of my report...
- 你去告诉他，我马上就会过去 - 是，将军
- Tell him I will be there as quickly as possible. - Yes, General.
（克林姆林宫艺术品仓库）
求你了...
Please. Please.
- 我要集中精力 - 雷肯
- I am trying to concentrate. - Lenkin.
- 怎么了？ - 将军同志，我们遇到麻烦了
- What is it? - It's terrible news, Comrade General.
那个复制品在运输过程中被偷了
The reproduction has been stolen in transit.
那个窃贼已经解决了，但是彩蛋掉进河里丢了
The thief was dealt with, but the egg was lost in the river.
你的无能会害死我们所有人
Your incompetence will destroy us all.
- 那就再做一个复制品 - 将军同志，我们没有时间了
- We'll have a replacement made. - There is no time, Comrade General.
我刚刚收到消息，两天之后就要不定期清点库存了
I have just been informed of an unscheduled inventory in two days.
雷肯，冷静点
Control yourself, Lenkin.
我会通知我们在伦敦的人，我们一定会找回彩蛋的
I'll tell our London people, we must have the genuine egg back.
希望能及时联络到他们
I hope we can reach them in time.
布索尼得标
Sold to Busoni.
下一件是48号
The next lot is number 48.
由名匠卡尔·法贝热为东方皇帝制作的绿金彩蛋
A superb green-gold Imperial Easter egg by Carl Faberge.
内部是透明绿色的珐琅，被黄金做成的枝叶所环绕
Enamelled in translucent green, enclosed by gold laurel-leaf trellis.
上面点缀着蓝色的宝石和四朵镶钻的黄金花
Set with blue sapphires and four petalled gold flowers with diamonds.
这东西能值多少钱？
How much should it fetch?
25到30万英镑，再高的话就疯了
£250-300, 000. Anything more'd be crazy.
...1897年，它被尼古拉斯沙皇使用过
...used by Tsar Nicholas in 1897 in Moscow.
“女士的藏品”
Property of a Lady.
看呐，这里的女士可真不少
Well, there are quite a few ladies here.
她不必亲自来这里，她可以让一个委托人代表她来
She wouldn't have to be here in person. She could be represented by proxy.
底价15万英镑，开始
I'll start it at £150, 000.
15万，16万
150, 60.
17万，17万
170. 170.
18万 19万
180.190.
20万，女士，他出价比你高
200. Against you, madam.
- 还有人出价吗？ - 那里有位女士
- Any more? - Now there is a lady.
22万英镑
£220, 000.
24万
240.
詹姆斯，多注意点拍卖的情况
James, stick to the business in hand.
26万
£260, 000.
28万
280.
30万英镑
£300, 000.
下面开始加两万
And 20?
先生，你要出价吗？
Are you bidding, sir?
32万，又有人出价了
£320,000. New bidder.
- 这可真有趣 - 你认识他吗？
- That's interesting. - You know him?
卡马尔·汗，通常是卖家
Kamal Khan. Usually a seller.
来历不明，勉强算是上层人士
Marginal quality from dubious sources.
38万英镑
£380, 000.
- 中间的男士出价40万 - 应该可以成交了
- 400 in the centre. - Well, that should do it.
- 卡马尔出了最高价 - 先生，你出价40万英镑
- Kamal has gone over the top. - Your bid, sir. 400, 000.
40万，还有出价更高的吗？
400, 000. Any more?
42.5万，又有人出价了
425. New bidder.
谢谢你，先生
Thank you, sir.
- 42.5万 - 你疯了吗？
- 425. - Have you gone mad?
我要看看他到底有多想买它
Let's see how badly he wants it.
45万
450.
45万，还有更高的吗？
450. 475?
The bid is 450. 475?
先生，那位先生的出价比您高
Against you, sir. No more than 450.
- 吉姆 - 最高价是45万英镑
- Jim? - The bid is £450, 000.
有人出价47.5万
I have 475.
50万英镑
£500,000.
最高价是50万英镑，还有更高的吗？
I have half a million pounds. All done?
还有更高的吗？
Any more?
先生，成交，50万英镑
Yours, sir, for £500, 000.
- 下一件拍品是... - 我们差点就要买下它了
- The next lot is... - We could have been stuck with it.
- 不会的，他一定会买它 - 为什么
- I doubt it. He had to buy it. - But why?
这就是我们要去查的事
That's what I intend to find out.
你没有权力出价去买那个彩蛋
You had no business bidding for that egg.
万一真的把它买下了，你想怎么办
What would you have done if you'd got it?
长官，我会说那是假的，然后拒绝付款
I would have claimed it was a fake, sir, and not paid.
拒绝付款
Not paid?
真的在我手上，我在拍卖会上把它调包了
Here's the original. I switched it with the fake during the auction.
天呐
Good God.
万一卖家发现了他买到的是赝品怎么办？
And what happens when the buyer discovers that?
如果是正常的买家，就会提出申诉
Well, he complains. If he's legitimate.
- 然后呢？ - 但是我觉得他不会提出申诉
- Well? - I don't think he will complain.
范宁和我说卡马尔通常是卖家，但这次他是买家
According to Fanning, this Kamal usually sells. Now he buys.
那个赝品会让他露出马脚
I believe that the fake will smoke him out.
我们的人跟踪他到了希思罗机场，他坐飞机去了新德里
Our tail followed him to Heathrow where he caught a plane to Delhi.
你也要去那里
You must go there, too.
我会通知印度分局的沙鲁丁，他会帮你去监视他
I'll alert Sadruddin, our man in Station I, to keep him under surveillance.
你坐下一班飞机去印度
Book yourself on the next flight out.
是，长官，我就剩55分钟了
Well, I've 55 minutes to catch it, sir.
- 邦德 - 长官
- Oh, Bond? - Sir?
走之前签一张通行证
Sign a chit for that egg before you go.
它现在是政府的财产了
It's government property now.
好的，长官
Of course, sir.
这首曲子不错，你收英镑吗？
Charming tune. You do take English money?
我只收一磅的金币
Only gold sovereigns.
请帮我拿一下
Please.
我叫维贾伊，是环球出口公司的特别采购员
I'm Vijay. Special expediter, Universal Exports.
- 邦德中校，欢迎来到印度 - 谢谢你，叫我詹姆斯就行
- Welcome to India, Commander Bond. - Thank you. Call me James.
- 沙鲁丁呢？ - 在那边，他在计程车里等你呢
- Where's Sadruddin? - Over here. Waiting in the taxi.
- 这种穿着不太合适 - 我讨厌蛇
- This was the wrong cover. - I hate snakes.
这是计程车，请坐下吧
Taxi. Please be comfortable.
- 邦德中校，我是沙鲁丁，印度分局的局长 - 你好啊
- Commander Bond, I am Sadruddin, Head of Section. - How do you do?
- 我已经给你定好酒店了 - 很好 我的行李呢
- I booked you in at the Shivnivas Hotel. - Good. My luggage?
已经送过去了
Gone ahead.
卡马尔·汗是个什么人？
What can you tell me about Kamal Khan?
被放逐的阿富汗王子，喜欢打马球、板球和网球
Exiled Afghan prince. Sportsman - polo, cricket, tennis.
- 我也会打一点网球 - 真的吗
- I play a bit myself. - Really?
事实上，我是卡马尔的俱乐部里的一名兼职网球运动员
As a matter of fact, I've got a part-time job as a pro at Kamal's club.
- 你学的怎么样？ - 我的反手拍进步了
- What have you learned so far? - My backhand's improved.
卡马尔的豪宅就在山顶上
Kamal lives there on the hill.
季风宫殿，那里守卫森严
The Monsoon Palace. It's heavily guarded.
我怎么才能见到他？
How do I get to him?
他差不多每天的下午和晚上都会在酒店的赌场里玩双陆棋
He plays backgammon most afternoon and evening at the hotel casino.
你是酒店的房客，所以也有会员的资格
As a guest, you're automatically a member.
- 我们一会儿在那里见面 - 我先去换身衣服
- Let's meet there later. - I'll change into something less casual.
给你这个，你玩蛇的时候可能会用到它
Here, you may need this to play with your asp.
早上好，我叫邦德，在这里预订了房间
Good morning. Name's Bond. I believe you have a reservation.
- 我们正在等您呢 - 很好
- We've been expecting you. - Good.
希望您在这里能玩的愉快
I hope you have a pleasant stay.
我想我会的
I'm sure I will.
谢谢你
Thank you.
先生，您的行李已经整理好了
Your luggage has been unpacked, sir.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
如果您有需要可以叫我
If I can be of further assistance...
- 您还有事吗？ - 没有了
- Anything at all? - Maybe later.
- 怎么样了？ - 少校也不是新手
- How's he doing? - The Major's no novice.
但是卡马尔已经赢了20万卢比了
But Kamal has won 200,000 rupees.
这回你可赢不了了吧
You'll have a job beating this.
我今天手气很好，要加倍吗？
I feel lucky. Shall we double?
当然要
Of course.
两万卢比
20,000 rupees.
- 怎么每次你出的时候都是豹子 - 总是这样
- Damn, always a double six when you need it. - Always.
- 你是怎么做到的 - 全靠手腕功夫
- How do you do it. - It's all in the wrist.
- 我就做不到 - 少校，要再来一局吗？
- It's hopeless. - Shall we have another game, Major?
- 一样的 - 好，再来一局
- Same stake? - Yes, I'll have another go.
你的好运气总会用完的
Your luck's got to run out some time.
能一起喝一杯吗
May I join you?
苏富比拍卖行 50万英镑
Sotheby's. Half a million pounds?
- 你是拍卖会上的那个人 - 没错
- The man at the auction. - Precisely.
你对人的面相的记性不错
You have a good memory for faces.
还有身材
And figures.
- 这不是巧合吧 - 没错
- This can't be a coincidence. - No.
- 你想喝点什么？ - 不用了，谢谢你
- What will you have? - Nothing, thank you.
下次见面时会愿意吗？
Some other time, perhaps?
谢谢你
Thank you.
七点
Six and one.
- 怎么样 - 看起来上校会赢
- Well? - Looks like the Major has got him.
少校，让我们玩得再刺激点吧
Why don't we make it interesting, Major?
加注到10万卢比怎么样
Double to 100, 000 rupees.
我不玩了，你的运气太好了
I can't accept. Not with your luck.
你赢了
You win.
如果是我，我就会继续加注
I would have taken that double, myself.
那您为什么不接替少校来试一下呢？您是...
Then why don't you take over the Major's position? Mr... ?
邦德
Bond.
詹姆斯·邦德，谢谢，我很愿意试一下
James Bond. Thank you, I'd be delighted.
赌注是10万卢比
100, 000 rupees, then.
十二点
Double six.
想要战胜这个可不是太容易，你说呢？
Not such a good double to accept, after all, was it?
- 再加一倍 - 好的
- Double. - Of course.
你得再掷出十二点才能赢
You can only win with a double six.
赌注是20万卢比
The stake is 200, 000 rupees.
你有现金吗？
Do you have the cash?
我想这个东西应该够了吧
Well, I think that this should be ample security.
你说呢？
Don't you?
请吧，邦德先生
Play, Mr Bond.
你得需要十足的好运气才能做到
You'll need a great deal of luck to get out of this.
运气
Oh, luck?
我想我应该沾沾你的手气
Well, then I shall use player's privilege,
用一下你的幸运骰子
and use your lucky dice.
全凭手腕功夫
It's all in the wrist.
十二点
Double sixes.
真想不到
Fancy that.
20万卢比
200, 000 rupees.
我要现金
I prefer cash.
- 换成现金给他 - 是，先生
- Get it cashed for him. - Yes, sir.
邦德先生，快去把钱花完吧
Spend the money quickly, Mr Bond.
卡马尔·汗，我正有此意
I intend to, Kamal Khan.
这是我的护身符
My security.
这是你的吗？
And yours?
看到了吗，也不全是凭手腕功夫
It's not really in the wrist, you know.
我应该去跟踪他们吗？
Should I be following them?
是的，不过我想他们会跟随这个而来的
Yes, but I think they'll be following this.
谢谢你
Thank you.
维贾伊会继续留在这里
Vijay will take you from here.
我会去查查卡马尔的底细
I'll see if I can find out more about Kamal.
很好，这个你拿着
Good. Hold on to these, will you?
这些应该够你买好几个月的咖喱了
Keep you in curry for a few weeks, won't it?
谢谢你，花天酒地的生活真好
Thank you. It's a wonderful racket, this.
维贾伊，我们有伴了
Vijay, we have company.
别担心，这是咱们公司的车
No problem. This is a company car.
从这下去
Step on it.
这样应该能甩掉他们了
This should shake 'em off.
多亏了这笔现金
Thank God for hard currency.
球赛结束，詹姆斯，坐稳了
Game, set and match. Hang on, James.
把头低下
Keep your head down.
谢谢你
Thank you.
（滚下我的床）
给你，接着吧
Here. Catch.
借用一下
Excuse me.
谢谢你，你还是自己把它吞回去吧
Thank you. You'd better stick this back yourself.
詹姆斯，到这来，快上车
James, over here. Come on.
维贾伊，我给你的钱呢
Vijay. The money I gave you.
有钞票了
Here. Rupees!
来的容易，花的也容易
Easy come, easy go.
这广告还真的有点用
It pays to advertise.
詹姆斯，这边走
This way, James.
Q
Ah, Q.
- 你好啊 - 大部分我不开心的时候都是因为你
- How are you? - Most unhappy, 007, thanks to you.
我怎么才能高质量的去完成工作呢
How can I be expected to maintain the quality of my work?
我接到命令就赶过来了，连设备都没有
Sent out here at a moment's notice.
你这里有细线吗？有人把刀刺进了我的钱包里
Have you any smaller thread? Someone stuck a knife in my wallet.
没刺中你，真是可惜
They missed you. What a pity.
凯伦，这个就麻烦你一下吧
Karen, see to that, will you?
我把我的枪也弄丢了
I've also mislaid my PPK.
- 还弄丢什么了？ - 就这些
- Anything else? - No, that's all.
该死
Blast.
Q，你没办法让它坚挺吗？
Having problems keeping it up, Q?
这个还在实验阶段
Experimental model.
- 你好啊，史密瑟斯 - 中校
- Hello, Smithers. - Commander.
- 真了不起 - 过来吧，我有东西要给你
- Smashing, Q. - Come on. I have a few things for you.
史密瑟斯，非常好
Very nice, Smithers.
Q，追踪器准备好了吗
Is the homing device ready yet, Q?
不只是追踪器
Not only a homing device
还有一个非常精密的麦克风
but an extremely delicate microphone as well.
就这样放进去
It goes in there like that.
现在注意，这是一支钢笔
Now, take a fountain pen.
转动笔套
Twist the top,
在这支笔的内部装有浓度非常高的王水
and a highly concentrated mixture of nitric and hydrochloric acid.
- 可以融化所有金属 - 很适合毒死作家
- Dissolves all metals. - Wonderful for poison-pen letters.
007，专心点
Pay attention, 007.
把笔帽顶端摘下来
Pull the top off the pen.
用这个非常灵敏的耳机，你可以收听到窃听器的声音
With this ultrasensitive earpiece, you can listen in on the bug.
这个追踪器可以和你手表上的无线电测距仪相匹配
The homing device is compatible with the radio directional finder in your watch.
如果你没把手表弄丢的话
If you haven't lost it.
非常好，Q，它在工作
That's amazing, Q. It does work.
那是什么？
What's that?
那是最新型的液晶电视
That's the latest liquid-crystal TV.
非常精巧
Very handy.
Q，图像很漂亮
Perfect image, Q.
Really, 007.
听着，我没时间去陪你玩这些幼稚的游戏
Look, I haven't time for these adolescent antics.
- 中校，我们只能做成这样了 - 非常漂亮，谢谢你
- It's the best we can do, commander. - It's beautiful. Thank you.
好了，你可以走了，我还有工作要做
Go on, get along. I've got my work to do.
- Q，我可以留下帮忙 - 谢谢你
- I'll give you a hand, Q. - Thank you.
别忘了这个
Don't forget this.
别让他那些坏习惯把你带坏了
Don't let him teach you any of his bad habits.
邦德先生，您的座位准备好了
Mr Bond, your table is ready.
- 我没有订座位 - 先生，您的客人在等您
- I didn't reserve one. - Your guest is waiting, sir.
这边请
This way, please.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你是改主意了吗？
You changed your mind.
- 我很高兴 - 是吗？
- I'm glad. - Are you?
好吧，这么说吧
Well, let's put it this way.
到目前为止，你是卡马尔的朋友中对我最友好的一个
So far, you are the least lethal and by far the prettiest of Kamal's friends.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这次见面是他让你来的还是你自己来的
So does he have a proposition for me, or do you?
他想和你做个交易
He suggests a trade.
用彩蛋换你的小命
The egg for your life.
我早就听说彩蛋的价格涨了很多，但这是不是太高了点？
I'd heard the price of eggs was going up, but isn't that a little high?
把账单计入几号房间
Charge it to Room ...
27号房间，香槟也一起算进去
Oh, 27. Along with the champagne, I suppose?
我会把它放到桌子上
I'll leave it at the desk.
你不介意吗？
You don't mind?
为什么？卡马尔·汗已经忘了我的长相了吗？
Why? Has Kamal forgotten what I look like already?
是我想要
It's for me.
所以说万一哪天我突然死了
So that if I depart this world suddenly,
你就有东西可以来怀念我了，对吗？
you'll have something to remember me by?
差不多就是这样
Something like that.
它会放进我的剪贴簿里，我会收集回忆
It's for my scrapbook. I collect memories.
那我们就来制造一些回忆吧
Well, let's get on with making a few.
我还想再来一杯
I need refilling.
当然可以
Of course you do.
我再去拿一瓶
I'll get some more.
不必麻烦了，我们来喝个交杯酒吧
Don't bother. We'll make yours a loving cup.
真是个好主意
What a good idea.
请原谅我的好奇心，这是什么？
Forgive my curiosity, but what is that?
这是我的小章鱼
That's my little octopussy.
早上好
Good morning.
Morning.
我不想吵醒你，但是既然你已经醒了
I didn't want to wake you. But since you're up,
我就可以亲口和你说再见了
I can say a proper goodbye.
现在几点了
What is the time?
风景很美，不是吗？
Beautiful view, isn't it?
- 我不知道要怎么去说再见 - 行动比语言更好
- I don't know how to say goodbye. - Actions speak louder than words.
一点没错
So right.
一 二 一 二
In. Out. In. Out.
加油，姑娘们
Come on, girls. In. Out.
收起船桨
Check oars.
我们已经找回彩蛋了
The egg has been recovered.
你应该高兴的
You should be pleased .
在它第一次被偷走之后我就很不高兴
I'm not pleased it was stolen in the first place.
就更别说窃贼已经知道它和我们有关系了
Nor that the thief knows enough to bring it here.
他显然是个喜欢冒险的人，想用这个来要挟我们
He's obviously an adventurer with possible blackmail on his mind.
反正现在他已经被带到季风宫殿了
Anyway, I have him as my guest at the Monsoon Palace.
他很快就会说出他到底知道什么
And he will tell us all he knows very quickly.
- 他到底是谁？ - 一个英国人
- Who is he? - Englishman.
喜欢彩蛋，由其是法贝热的
Likes eggs. Preferably Faberge.
还有色子，尤其是是灌了铅的
And dice. Preferably loaded.
他叫詹姆斯·邦德
His name is James Bond.
把他带到这里来
Bring him here.
他是个很危险的人，在他招供之后，我们必须除掉他
He's dangerous. After he's talked, we must get rid of him immediately.
不行
No.
我想你应该是不会把“不行”改成“行”的
A "no" from you has little chance of becoming a "yes".
所以本次谈话就到此结束吧
I assume, therefore, that the meeting is over.
但是你正在犯一个很严重的错误
But you're making a serious mistake.
到目前为止 这里的服务品质都非常的好
Well, so far I can't complain about the valet service.
晚上8点吃晚饭
Dinner. 8 o'clock.
- 晚上好，邦德先生 - 晚上好
- Good evening, Mr Bond. - Good evening.
休息好了吗？
Well rested?
你和玛格达小姐应该已经见过面了
I believe you and Miss Magda have met.
- 见面的时候我非常高兴 - 你太客气了
- It was a pleasure. - You're too kind.
可以开始用餐了吗？蛋奶酥可不能再等了
You don't mind if we start? The souffle can't wait.
请允许我在晚餐的时候问一个不太合适的问题
At the risk of appearing to be making light dinner conversation,
我为什么会在这里？
may I ask exactly why I am here?
我是说，你已经拿到彩蛋了
I mean, after all, you do have the egg.
没错，但是我们还没有统一的答案
True. But we don't have all the answers.
好吧，如果有争论的话，我不会说话的
Well, supposing, for argument's sake, I don't feel like talking?
别担心，你会说的
Don't worry, you will.
让我猜猜看
Let me guess.
夹棍，还有烙铁
Thumbscrews and hot coals.
不是，我们的方法比那可要复杂多了
Hardly. We're much more sophisticated than that.
- 硫喷妥钠 - 那太粗鲁了 并且很不可靠
- Sodium Pentothal? - A bit crude. Very unreliable.
我们更喜欢混有强效迷幻剂的箭毒
We prefer curare with an effective psychedelic compound.
保证会有效
Guaranteed results.
- 但是脑部会造成永久性伤害 - 很不幸的副作用
- But with permanent brain damage. - An unfortunate side effect.
这是我们的名菜之一
One of our specialities.
馅料酿羊头
Stuffed sheep's head.
很奇怪 当我被盯着看的时候什么食欲都没有
It's odd, but when I'm stared at I seem to lose my appetite.
对了，谢谢你的晚饭
Oh, thank you for dinner.
那么就明天再见了
Until tomorrow, then.
- 好了，我也要说再见了 - 我还可以再喝一杯
- Well, I'll say good night. - I could come in for a nightcap.
或许改天的吧
Some other time, perhaps.
你想进来喝一杯酒吗，不必了
I don't suppose you'd care for a nightcap? No.
我想您这一路上肯定很愉快
I trust you had a pleasant flight.
请跟我来，我们已经把所有东西都准备好了
If you step this way, I think you will find everything is in order.
卡马尔·汗，你们的工匠的手艺可真是不错
Congratulations on the quality of your workmanship, Kamal Khan.
谢谢你，奥尔洛夫将军
Thank you, General Orlov.
您可以看到 它每一处的尺寸都是严格的按照
As you can see, each piece has been meticulously duplicated
雷肯给我们的数据复制的
according to Lenkin's specifications.
很好，把它放到直升机上去
Good. Have it put aboard the helicopter.
- 能信任他们吗？ - 我保证他们会守口如瓶的
- Can they be trusted? - I assure you of their silence.
我们两个人都下了极大的赌注
We are both playing for enormous stakes.
我会得到我想要的
I get what I want
你也会得到真的珠宝
then you get the genuine jewellery.
没错
Exactly...
精准的时间控制非常重要
The precise timing will be essential.
记住，任何事情都不能改变计划
Remember: nothing must be changed.
一周之后的今天，在东德的马克思市
One week from today, in Karl-Marx-Stadt.
- 马克思市 - 没错
- Karl-Marx-Stadt. - Correct.
- 事情都办好了吗？ - 都按您的吩咐办好了
- Everything taken care of? - As you ordered, Excellence.
- 你又找回彩蛋了？ - 是从一个窃贼的手中找到的
- So, you recovered it? - From an accomplice of the thief.
马上把他杀掉
He must be eliminated at once.
不能再有任何安全上的问题
There must be no further security breach.
这个假的已经引起不少麻烦了
This fake has caused enough trouble.
我得走了
I must go.
我对你的表现非常满意
Everything has been most satisfactory.
奥尔洛夫将军，您太客气了
Most kind, General Orlov.
杀了邦德
Get Bond.
那个英国人跑了
The Englishman has escaped.
他跑不远的，我们会抓到他的
He won't go very far. We'll track him.
很好
Good.
让我们来运动一下吧
Let the sport commence.
快拦住他
Head him off.
坐下
Sit!
找到他了
We have him.
围住他，他在那里
Go round. He's in there.
不要出声
Hiss off.
不要让他跑了
Don't let him get away.
过来，老兄，快过来
C'mom, buddy, c'mon.
- 哥们，你还好吗 - 我很好
- Hey, you all right, buddy? - I'm fine.
你是我们这个团的吗？
Are you with our group?
不是，女士，我是经济团的
No, ma'am. I'm with the economy tour.
邦德先生真是个非常罕见的人
Mr Bond is indeed a very rare breed.
不过马上就要死了
Soon to be made extinct.
属于蓝圈章鱼
Genus Hapalochlaena.
它的毒液在数秒钟之内就可致人死亡
Produces a venom that's invariably fatal in seconds.
游艇上就有这种旗帜
The barge had that sign.
是的，那艘游艇属于一个住在水上宫殿的女富豪
Yes. It belongs to a wealthy woman who lives on the floating palace.
这个女人是谁？
Who is she?
没有人知道她的真实姓名，人们都叫她八爪女
No one knows her real name, but she's known as Octopussy.
我听卡马尔说过这个名字
That's the name I heard at Kamal's.
我听说整个岛上都是美女，不允许男人进入
I hear that island's full of beautiful women. No men allowed.
真的吗，性别歧视
Really? Sexual discrimination.
我一定要亲自去看一下
I'll definitely have to pay it a visit.
晚上好
Good evening.
我正在想你什么时候会来呢
I wondered when you might arrive.
所以你就是神秘的八爪女.
So you are the mysterious Octopussy.
你就是詹姆斯·邦德
And you are James Bond.
编号007，可以合法杀人
007, licensed to kill.
我是你今天晚上的目标吗？
Am I to be your target for tonight?
不确定
Not necessarily.
那要看你能告诉我多少关于珠宝走私的事
Depends how much you tell me about jewellery smuggling.
还有为什么我们的特工会在东柏林被杀
And why one of our agents was killed in East Berlin.
我不知道这件事
I know nothing about that.
你还记得德克斯特·斯迈思少校吗？
You remember Major Dexter Smythe?
被派去抓捕他的人就是你，对吗？
You were sent out to arrest him, weren't you?
看来你了解的事还真不少
You seem to have done your homework.
谢谢，我记得，斯迈思从军队退役之后加入了英国情报部门
Thank you. Yes. Smythe, after a brilliant military career, joined our secret service.
他的任务是找出落入朝鲜手中的一批中国金条
His mission was to recover a cache of Chinese gold, seized in North Korea.
他和他在当地的向导都失踪了
Both he and his native guide disappeared.
黄金也没有找到
The gold was never found.
二十年之后，你被派去抓捕他
And 20 years later you were sent after him.
后来向导的尸体被找到了，头骨里有一枚斯迈思枪里的子弹
The guide's body turned up with a bullet still in his skull from Smythe's revolver.
我追踪斯迈思到了斯里兰卡
I traced Smythe to Sri Lanka,
在我带他回去之前，我给了他24小时去处理好自己的事
and gave him 24 hours to clear up his affairs before I took him back.
他宁愿选择自杀也不愿意去面对军事法庭的羞辱
He committed suicide rather than face the disgrace of a court martial.
这些和你有什么关系
What's the connection?
他是我的父亲，我一直希望命运能让我们俩见面
He was my father. I'd hoped fate would bring us together one day.
好去为他报仇吗
To avenge him?
不是，好去感谢你给了他一个体面的结局
No, to thank you for giving him an honourable alternative.
进来
Come in.
卡马尔·汗要见你
Kamal Khan to see you.
邦德逃走了
Bond has escaped.
- 你真是大意 - 很抱歉
- How careless of you. - I apologise.
你来的正好，来见一下我的新客人吧
By the way, I'd like you to meet my new house guest.
你或许会说我是你们家的老朋友了
An old friend of the family, you might say.
真好
How lovely.
你求生的方式真是让人讨厌
You have a nasty habit of surviving.
你应该知道 这叫适者生存
You know what they say about the fittest.
八爪女，我很希望能有另一个机会去好好招待一下邦德先生
Octopussy, I'd enjoy another opportunity to take care of Mr Bond personally.
我会亲自招待好邦德先生的
I will take care of Mr Bond myself.
晚安
Good night.
好好放松一下吧
And enjoy yourselves.
邦德先生
Mr Bond.
我父亲后来成为了章鱼教的领袖
My father became a leading authority on octopi.
他深爱着它们，他把我昵称为八爪女
He loved them. His pet name for me was Octopussy.
邦德先生，走私不是英国情报部门的管辖范围
Mr Bond, smuggling is no concern of the secret service.
我也从未违反过英国法律
I've violated no British law.
你可以自由的离开这里，但我更希望你能在这里多留几天
You are free to leave, but I'd much prefer if you stayed as my guest for a few days.
我很荣幸
I'd like that.
格温多林，带邦德先生去他的房间
Gwendoline, show Mr Bond to his room.
晚安，邦德先生
Good night, Mr Bond.
明天早上见
Till the morning, then.
蜜琪
Midge.
好好招待邦德先生 但是要先把他房间周围的警卫加倍
Extend Mr Bond every courtesy, but double the guard on his quarters.
他说岛上的戒备非常森严
He says the island is heavily guarded.
我们不想成为那女人的敌人
We don't want to make enemies with the woman.
绝对不能伤到八爪女
The woman must not be harmed.
当我父亲的黄金花完之后，当初在香港替他卖掉黄金的人
When Father's gold ran out, the people in Hong Kong who'd disposed of it for him
给我提供了一个走私钻石的机会
offered me a commission to smuggle some diamonds.
我发现我对这种事很有天赋
I discovered I had a talent for it.
所以你就干上了这个
So you went into business for yourself?
是的，但是我需要一个组织，所以我重建了古老的章鱼教
Yes, but I needed an organisation, so I revived the old Octopus cult.
你是从哪里找来这么多的美女的？
Well, then. Where did you recruit all these lovelies?
在东南亚有很多这样的人
There are many of them all over Southeast Asia,
想找一个导师，寻求精神修炼，谁知道这是什么？
looking for a guru, spiritual discipline, who knows what.
我训练她们
I train them.
给了她们人生目标、姐妹情谊，还有富足的生活
Give them a purpose, a sisterhood and a way of life.
- 通过犯罪吗？ - 通过生意
- In crime? - In business.
我有很多产业，商场、酒店，还有巡回马戏团
I have diversified into shipping, hotels, carnivals and circuses.
- 他还在岛上吗？ - 你肯定是在开玩笑
- Is he still there? - You must be joking.
007在一座美女如云的岛上
007 on an island populated exclusively by women?
不到天亮是见不到他的
We won't see him till dawn.
- 我等到午夜再来换班 - 没问题
- I'll relieve you at midnight. - No problem.
我们要到别的地方去吗？
Are we going somewhere?
我明天早上要到欧洲去谈生意
I have to go to Europe tomorrow on a business trip.
真是可惜，我正想好好的享受一下生活呢
Oh, that's a pity. I was just beginning to enjoy myself.
我觉得你应该留下来，我只去一个星期
I think you should stay. I'll only be gone a week.
等我回来的之后，我们可以讨论一下未来
When I come back we'll discuss the future.
我不能保证你回来的时候我还会在这里
Well, I can't guarantee that I'll be here when you return.
詹姆斯，我们两个是同一类人
Oh, James. We're two of a kind.
以你的聪明才智，如果愿意冒险绝对会发大财
There are vast rewards for a man of your talents willing to take risks.
- 我不会干这个 - 你可真有原则
- I'm not for hire. - A man of principle.
有人想出钱买你的命
With a price on his head.
你当然是为了你的女王和国家做事
Naturally, you would do it for Queen and country.
我没有国家，也没有人想要我的命
I have no country, I have no price on my head.
我这样的人不需要向你这样一个收钱的杀手道歉
I don't have to apologise to you, a paid assassin, for what I am.
不要
No.
你说的没错
You're right.
我们是同一类人
We are two of a kind.
詹姆斯
James.
Q？
Q?
出什么事了？
Is something wrong?
没什么
Not really.
只是有一种感觉
Just a feeling.
那为什么不回到床上去呢？
Why don't you come back to bed?
快走开
Move!
詹姆斯
James.
小心
Watch it!
快走
Come on.
小心
Careful.
把枪给我
Give me the gun!
维贾伊怎么了？
What happened to Vijay?
我发现他的时候他还活着
He was alive when I found him.
- 他说什么了吗？ - 只说是卡马尔·汗的人
- Did he say anything? - Only say was "It was Kamal's men."
不会再发生这种事了
No more problems.
- 通知M到柏林和我见面 - 为什么
- You better signal M to meet me in Berlin. - Why?
我要去调查一下马克思市的巡回马戏团
Well, I have to go to a circus in Karl-Marx-Stadt.
已经证实了，009被杀的时候八爪女的马戏团也在东柏林
We verified the Octopussy Circus was in East Berlin when we lost 009.
在马克思市的东部
Karl-Marx-Stadt is further east.
奥尔洛夫将军为什么要参与珠宝走私呢？
Why would General Orlov participate in a jewellery caper?
珠宝走私，长官，请允许我做个不恰当的比喻
Well, the jewellery, sir, I think is, if you'll forgive the analogy,
只是章鱼触手的一小部分
only the tip of the tentacle.
这是你的新身份
Here's the ID you'll need.
查尔斯·莫顿，是来自利兹的制造商代表
Charles Moreton, manufacturer's representative from Leeds
到东柏林来参观家具工厂
visiting furniture factories in East Germany.
- 卡尔会带你进去 - 没问题
- Karl will take you in. - No problem.
记住，007，你只能靠自己
Remember, 007, you're on your own.
长官，谢谢你的关心
Thank you, sir. That's a great comfort.
（你们正在离开美国控制区）
米施卡
Mischka.
我想你应该认识伯尔奇同志，他是埃米塔什博物馆的馆长
Of course you know Comrade Borchoi, the curator of the Hermitage.
他刚刚从列宁格勒赶来
He just arrived from Leningrad.
罗曼诺夫之星
The Romanov Star.
他们给火车换轨的时候你留在这里看着珠宝
Stay here with the jewellery while they switch the car to the main track.
你也留下
You stay, also.
10万吨TNT当量
100 kiloton yield.
它的威力和影响范围与美国的中型核弹完全相同
The effects are indistinguishable from the American medium-yield bomb.
这是引爆器，现在听好
The detonator, now listen carefully.
预设四个小时之后引爆
It is pre-set for a four-hour delay.
在这里设置引爆时间
Set time for the explosion here.
激活需要把它插入弹体 顺时针旋转90度
To activate, insert and twist the lever a quarter-turn clockwise.
爆炸的时候至少要离开20英里
Be at least 20 miles away when it goes off.
这些珠宝能让我们在苏黎世赚三亿美金
The jewellery should net us 300 million in Zurich.
现在我们先得穿过边界
We still have to cross the border.
我得走了
I must go.
再见了，小姐
Au revoir, dear lady.
祝你好运
Good luck.
把那筒子拿过来
Bring the canister.
放到车里
Put it in the car.
别管它了，我们走
Leave that. Let's go.
再待一会儿，坐到箱子上，双手放到膝盖上，快点
Let's stay. Sit on that box. Hands on your knees. Come on, move.
为什么火车上会有炸弹？
Why is that bomb on the train?
- 你是什么人？ - 英国特工
- Who are you? - British secret service.
你现在更应该关心的是怎么活着离开这里
You should be more concerned about getting out of here alive.
我现在更关心的是在美国的空军基地里即将爆炸的核弹
I am more concerned about an atomic bomb exploding on a US Air Force base.
你不会想挑起核战争的，如果美国报复怎么办？
You can't be inviting a nuclear war. What happens when the US retaliates?
向谁报复
Against whom?
天呐，当然了
My God. Of course.
我们的早期预警系统会排除这是俄国或者其他国家
Our early-warning system will rule out the bomb having come from Russia
发起的攻击
or anywhere else.
所有的人都会把这当成是美国核弹的意外爆炸
Everyone will assume incorrectly that it was a US bomb triggered accidentally.
这将会是最合理的解释
That would be the most plausible explanation.
欧洲就会实行单方面的核裁军
Europe will insist on disarmament,
边境的防御能力就会大幅下降，你的军队可以轻松突破
leaving every border undefended for you to walk across at will.
至于这场爆炸会让
It doesn't matter a damn to you
成千上万无辜的人死于非命，这不是你所关心的事
that thousands of innocent people will die in your accident.
这样总比让莫斯科的那群老政客
Better than letting a handful of old men in Moscow
在核裁军谈判中逐步丧失优势要好得多
bargain away our advantage in disarmament talks.
将军，站起来，你要去阻止火车
On your feet, General. You're going to stop that train.
- 太晚了 - 你可以在边界上拦下火车
- It's too late. - You can stop it at the border.
杀了他
Kill him!
到车站去
Get to the station!
拦住那辆车
Stop that car!
停车
Stop.
跟着那辆车
Follow that car.
卡马尔·汗让我们在穿越边界之前一直留在这里
Kamal Khan says we are to stay here until we cross the border.
这是奥尔洛夫将军的车
The licence plate is General Orlov's.
我们发现了这个
We have discovered this.
- 奥尔洛夫将军现在在哪？ - 有报告说他正在前往边界
- Where is General Orlov now? - Last reported heading for the border.
我得到那辆火车上去
I must get to that train.
停火
Stop!
卑劣的小偷
A common thief.
你是整个军队的耻辱
The disgrace to the uniform.
没错，但是明天
Yes. But tomorrow,
我将会成为
I shall be a hero
苏联的英雄
of the Soviet Union.
现在是11点45分
It is now 11.45.
表演会在3点开始
The performance begins at 3.
留出表演延迟的时间，设置到3点45分引爆
Allowing for delays, set the bomb to detonate at 3.45.
我们必须在3点15分之前离开基地
We must leave the base by 3.15.
我想你们都不会迟到的
I take it none of you will be late.
去看好珠宝
The jewellery.
- 你认出那是谁了吗？ - 没有
- Did you recognise him? - No.
在这陪着她
Stay here with her.
车顶上有人
On the roof. Trouble.
米施卡
Mischka.
这一刀
And this,
是为我哥哥报仇
for my brother.
这是为009报仇
And that's for 009.
戈宾达会好好看着珠宝的
Gobinda will stay with the jewellery.
将军，我得失陪一下，我要去安排一下行程，好好欣赏表演吧
General, excuse me. I have some travel arrangements to make. Enjoy the show.
- 谢谢你 - 我想将军一定会非常喜欢的
- Thank you. - I'm sure he'll get a big blast out of this.
我相信他是不会失望的
I know he won't be disappointed.
- 那是邦德 - 很好，让他去吧
- That was Bond. - Good. Let him keep going.
已经来不及了，正好把他也除掉
He'll be late and we'll be rid of him too.
棒极了，对吗？
Great, isn't it?
太棒了
Fantastic.
- 真精彩 - 将军
- Marvellous. - General,
如果我偷了你的钱包，会被关多久的禁闭呢？
How long would I get in the brig if I stole your wallet?
- 大约两年 - 这么久啊
- About two years. - That long?
既然是这样，那我还是还给你吧
Well, in that case, I'd better return it.
你这个小坏蛋
Son of a gun.
（美军费尔德空军基地）
基地指挥官在哪里？
Where's the Base Commander?
出示你的马戏团通行证
Let's see your circus pass.
可恶，这是紧急事件
Damn it, man, it's urgent.
下车，把手举起来
Get out. Hands up!
上尉，有个疯子开着一辆赃车闯了进去
Captain, a nut went through in a stolen car.
点名要找指挥官，他穿着一件个红色的衬衫
Wants the Base Commander, and he's wearing a red shirt.
他在那
There he is.
就是那个穿红色衬衫的家伙
Go after that guy in the red shirt.
在拖车后面
Behind the trailers.
所有人继续搜查，他一定就在这附近
Keep searching, you guys. He's gotta be around here somewhere.
你的人去搜查一下拖车底下
Look under the trailer, you guys.
- 女士们、先生们 - 嘿，有别人在里面吗？
- Ladies and gentlemen... - Hey. Is anyone else in there?
这是第一次在这里表演的节目，挑战死亡极限的人肉炸弹
For the first time in this country, the death-defying human cannonball.
我很荣幸的为大家介绍，这是勇敢无畏的弗朗西斯科
I have the pleasure in presenting to you Francisco the Fearless.
疑犯穿着小丑的服装
The suspect's wearing a clown suit. Over.
就是他
That's him.
等一下，老兄，跟我们走
Hold it, buddy. You're coming with us.
将军，大炮里有一枚炸弹
General, there's a bomb in that cannon.
当然了，不然炸弹还能放到哪？
Sure. Where else would a bomb be?
这小丑真不错
Great clown.
我是认真的，我是英国特工
I'm deadly serious. I'm a British agent.
什么？
What?
看在上帝的份上，快告诉他我是谁
For God's sake, tell him who I am.
卡马尔和奥尔洛夫骗了你，他们把珠宝从火车上拿走了
Kamal and Orlov double-crossed you. I saw them take the jewellery off the train.
这样你应该相信了吧
Does that convince you?
长官，核弹设定在3点45分引爆，现在只剩90秒了
Sir, that bomb is set to explode at 3.45. That's 90 seconds from now.
将军，他不是喝醉了就是个疯子
General, this man's either drunk or crazy.
他会毁了整个行动的
He'll destroy the entire operation.
你们俩，抓住他，快抓住他
You two, grab that man. Hold him.
该死，快放开我
Damn it. Let go.
快放开我，那里面有炸弹
Let me go, there's a bomb in there.
放开他
Let him go.
所有人，安静
Quiet, everyone.
是现在吗？
Now?
谢谢你，干得好
Thank you. Great job, sir.
卡马尔去哪了？
Where was Kamal going?
回印度了
Back to India.
各位观众，刚才出了点紧急状况，不过现在已经没事了
Folks, we've had an emergency, but everything is all right now.
你和你们的家人都是安全的
You and your families are safe.
现在请各位有序的离开这里，谢谢大家
Now, please leave the tent in an orderly manner. Thank you.
- 飞机已经加满油了 - 我们早上就离开
- The plane is refuelled. - We'll take off at sunrise.
- 我的黄金许可证带了吗？ - 是的 先生
- Are the gold certificates on board? - Yes, Excellence.
把这些也带走，美元、英镑、法郎，还有马克
We'll take these also. Dollars, pounds, francs, marks.
我可以自己印钞票
I can always print my own.
- 怎么了？ - 是女孩们在勾引男人
- What is that? - Girls selling themselves.
很好，这可以让他们忙上一阵子了
Good. It will keep the men occupied.
我不想让他们看到我离开
I don't want them to see me leave.
跳
Now.
帮我一下
Give us a hand.
快点
Come on.
我们走，都解决了吗？
Let's go. All set?
举起来
Lift.
就这样，稳住
That's it. Steady.
- 你去让他们给马都装上马鞍 - 是，先生
- Make sure the horses are saddled. - Yes, Excellence.
我等会去和你会和
I'll join you in a few minutes.
- 你以为你真能逃得掉吗？ - 奥尔洛夫背叛了我们
- Do you really think you can escape me? - Orlov betrayed us.
我发誓我根本不知道核弹的事
I swear I knew nothing about the bomb.
八爪女，我们是合作伙伴，也是朋友
We're partners, we're friends. Octopussy.
我是不会做任何伤害你的事的
I would never do anything to hurt you.
你想让我和成千上万无辜的人一起被炸死
You left me to be killed along with thousands of innocent people.
八爪女
Octopussy.
你看，我把这个给你带回来了
Look. I was bringing you this.
我们会发大财的
We can make millions.
抓住她，她能让我们安全的离开这里的
Take her. She's our ticket out of here.
- Q，我相信你能操纵这东西 - 这是依靠热空气的
- I trust you can handle this contraption, Q. - It goes by hot air.
你肯定能行
Oh, then you can.
- 她们已经控制住局势了 - 但是我没看到八爪女
- They're doing fine. - But I don't see Octopussy.
- 在那里，她有麻烦了 - 把你的脏手拿开
- There she is. She's in trouble. - Get your hands off me.
- 我会降下去 - 不，上升
- I'll take her down. - No. Up!
你到底想要去哪？007，别犯傻了，快点回来
Where are you going? Look, don't be an idiot, 007. Come back.
杀了他
Kill him.
快点
Come on.
你们要干什么？别闹了
What are you doing? Cut it out.
我们没有时间了... 等一会也行
We haven't time for that. Later perhaps.
快，快点
Come on. Giddap.
快点
Come on.
他会害死我们的，出去杀了他
He'll kill us all. Go out and get him.
- 出去 - 快点
- Out there? - Go.
是，先生
Yes, Excellence.
跳
Jump!
我国政府坚决否认发生过这件事情
My government categorically denies the incident ever occurred.
但是我们还是想请邦德先生归还我们的国宝
However, we request Bond to return one of our most historic treasures,
罗曼诺夫之星
the Romanov Star.
考虑到英国和苏联的双边关系，我们会归还给你们的
In the interests of our Anglo-Soviet relationships, that can be arranged.
邦德中校现在在哪
Where is Commander Bond?
很不幸，邦德在行动中受了非常严重的伤
Well, unfortunately owing to the serious nature of his injuries
他现在不适合进行长途旅行
he's still not fit enough to travel.
一 二 一 二
In. Out. In. Out.
- 我希望... - 什么？
- I wish... - What?
我真希望你的身体现在不是这么虚弱
I wish you weren't in such a weakened condition.
詹姆斯
James!